[Music]
hi I'm Bonita Roy and I want to talk a
little bit about the master's degree
program in consciousness studies the
Graduate Institute really offers a very
unique program on the one hand like
similar programs it's a survey course in
consciousness studies so you can get an
overview of what is consciousness what
is consciousness from a developmental
perspective you can get a view from an
evolutionary perspective we look at
consciousness studies from an
anthropological perspective from a
neurological and narrow down a Meccano
phenomenological perspective and we also
do a little dabbling about a
cosmological perspective we also work a
lot with an east-west fusion so we look
at consciousness from a Buddhist
perspective and Taoist and Zen
perspective but also from recent work in
neuro
phenomenology and mind and life sciences
we look at consciousness studies from
the direction of ethics and we also work
with consciousness studies in certain
modules as transformative coaching and
creativity and in transpersonal
psychology so that's you get the whole
bones of the territory of consciousness
studies but what CGI does that is unique
and different is that we integrate that
with direct experience with pointing out
instructions and mindfulness training so
every point along the way as you're
studying a domain from let's say a more
academic or third-person perspective
you're realizing the truth or the
insight of that perspective in your own
lived experience and so this is an what
we call integrative phenomenology we
integrate that in with the third-person
objective understanding we always make
it land with our own direct experience
and that is true of whether or not
you're a busy mother or a very renowned
professional or student or a hobbyist or
someone that's interested in a spiritual
journey we really cover a lot of
different ways for that to understand
and I think the third critical feature
of the Graduate Institute program is the
cohort experience we spend a lot of time
reflecting our understanding and our
insight and our inquiry back into
cooperative inquiry so the group grows
and understands and learns and directs
their learning as a whole and that
dialogue and that discussion and those
friendships and that engagement gets
deeper and richer over the two years so
it's really a great adventure there's
nothing like it and its really
world-class education
[Music]